Okay, so to explain this next part, I
actually brought in um the function and
the string array from a previous video.
So here um we've got that string array
with extra spaces and different
capitalization. And here we've got the
function that will take an input array
and take an input function. So if we
want to call this input function apply
to array
um maybe we'll say let result equal
apply to array and then we'll take in an
input array. We'll pass in that string
array that we got earlier and then we'll
put a comma and now we want to take an
input function. So I could pass in
cleanup string here but maybe let's say
I hadn't defined that yet. So what I'm
going to show you is you can take this
very shortand that we just used and use
it here. So rather than passing in a
function with a name, we can pass in an
anonymous function. So we can say messy
string
and then do that and then say messy
string.trim
dot to uppercase.
And so what we're saying is
um we've defined a function here and
we've given an array. So we'll take this
function and we'll call it right here.
And it's going to be called input
function inside of this um function. But
outside of it, we don't really need a
name because we're not going to use this
again. Um I am going to save this and
we're going to put a breakpoint on this
line when we get over to our code just
so you can see it in action.
Okay. So, we'll inspect our page. We'll
come to sources.
We'll go back over and make sure I
actually saved this page.
And we're just going to hit go live
again because it'll be easier. Okay. All
right.
So, here we've got our function. Let's
put a break point on line 36 and we'll
reload the page. Okay. So, we're about
to call this apply to array string. or
sorry apply to array function. We hit
the next. So what is in the input array?
Um it's text hello world and hi all that
have extra spaces and different
capitalization. What is the input
function? Well, it's an anonymous
function. It takes in an input of messy
string, trims it, and uppercases it. So
now we'll hit the next button and we'll
enter our array. What are we sending
into the function? Um, we're going to
send in input array at the zero
position, which is extra spaces and the
word hello. If we hit next, it comes
over here to where we defined the
function. So, what is messy string? It's
hello cuz we took it as an input. And
then now we're going to trim it and
uppercase it. And then we're going to
return it to the array. Now, if we look
at the array, now it says hello. So, we
can see that defining this function
directly inside of where we called a
different function, it works. And it's
much shorter than if we had to define
the function on separate lines and then
pass it in. So if you're only ever going
to use the function once, maybe we're
only ever going to use this cleanup
string once. We can just define it
directly inside of the function that
uses it. So it defines the function,
passes it in. So now when you hover over
input function, it now has a function
inside of it. And then it uses that
function and stores the results. And
that is why we might want to use lambda
functions. As a matter of fact, there
are a lot of built-in functions that
need us to give them a function. So, we
could define it separately like we were
doing before where we define function
cleanup string, write the return, and
then pass in that function to those
functions. Or now that we know how to
write it on one line, we can write it on
one line directly inside of the input.